Browse the pages, read all the headlines and look at all the pictures.
Read the captions.
Italic text is often some type of summary.
Is it a whole book?
Read the back.
Do you know anything in the subject since before?
Are there ways to get more understanding?
For example, a movie on the subject or any shorter article to read.
The understanding gives the brain something to hook up the new information.
It makes it easier to remember.
Do not read several hours in a row.
Put a clock in five minutes and read concentrated.
Late time.
If you read half-focused for an hour, you can easily lose yourself in the text-
-And must read about several times.
Five focused minutes give more.